(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
LETTER☆彡
Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2023
Are you ready?
白上フブキ 生誕祭 2023、スタート！
Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2023, START!
夢見た景色は
The scenery I dreamed of
まだ遠くても
is still far away, but
一歩ずつ踏みしめてきたんだ
I've been taking it one step at a time.
見上げた空に
In the sky I looked up at,
瞬く星が
the twinkling stars
僕らの道を照らしてくれた
illuminated our path.
ありがとうを込めて歌うよ
I'll sing with all my thanks,
君に届くように
so that it reaches you.
贈るよ LETTER
I'm sending you this LETTER.
躓きそうな夜もあったけど
There were nights I almost stumbled,
君の声が背中を押した
but your voice pushed me forward.
重なる想い繋がるメロディ
Overlapping feelings, a connecting melody,
何処にいたってひとりじゃないから
because no matter where you are, you're not alone.
いつまでも変わらないキズナ
A bond that will never change,
大切に抱きしめていこう
let's keep holding it dear.
キラキラ輝くこの瞬間を
This sparkling, shining moment
いつの日か宝物になる
will become a treasure someday.
溢れるほどの愛を込めて
With overflowing love,
君の元へと届けに行くよ
I'm going to deliver it to you.
心から伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you from the bottom of my heart,
いつもそばにいてくれてありがとう
thank you for always being by my side.
広がる世界 新しい明日
一緒に描いていきたい
The expanding world, a new tomorrow
I want to draw them together with you.
どんな時も信じているよ
No matter when, I believe in you,
最高の笑顔見せて
so show me your best smile.
夢の続きを奏で続けよう
Let's keep playing the continuation of our dream,
どこまでも響くように
so it resonates everywhere.
贈るよ LETTER
I'm sending you this LETTER.
キラキラ輝くこの瞬間を
This sparkling, shining moment
いつの日か宝物になる
will become a treasure someday.
溢れるほどの愛を込めて
With overflowing love,
君の元へと届けに行くよ
I'm going to deliver it to you.
心から伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you from the bottom of my heart,
いつもそばにいてくれてありがとう
thank you for always being by my side.
2023.10.5
Fubuki Shirakami Birthday Live
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
本日の主役
Today's Star
LETTER☆彡
KINGWORLD
now fubuking...
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD
アイノウ僕らのTRUEな世界
I know our TRUE world
War...僕らのKINGWORLD
War... our KINGWORLD
アイノウ僕らのTRUEな世界
I know our TRUE world
混沌とワンダーランド
Chaos and wonderland
電脳とアンバランス
Cyber and unbalance
あふれそう the 大変！
Overflowing, it's a mess!
でも異常・机上も We go on
But anomaly and armchair theories, we go on
コンニチハ・バーチャライズ
Hello virtualize
退屈はカスタマイズ？
Boredom is customized?
楽しくなりそうだ！
It looks like it's going to be fun!
ワナビーこれでステンバイ
Wannabe, standby with this
「望みは？」
"Wishes?"
「世界制覇？」
"World domination?"
シロかクロか頂上か実力か
White or black? Top spot or skill?
アタマかカラダか
Head or body?
いやいやシッポを忘れちゃいないかね！？
Wait, haven't you forgotten your tail!?
でもでも好き嫌いも営美なんでもいいんだ
But still, likes and dislikes, aesthetic, anything is fine
キミと一緒な世界なら
If it's a world with you
僕らの
Our
KINGWORLD
アイノウ僕らのTRUEな世界
I know our TRUE world
フリもムキも全部全部詰め込んで！
Fake and sincere, pack it all in!
サドデスにカタカタな魔物(モンスター)
The clattering monster in the sadist
アイも気まぐれなトリック☆スター
Love is also a capricious trickster
「誰のこと？」なんて言うものか！
"Whose business is it?" As if I'd say that!
ようこそ。
Welcome.
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD
新世界シンドローム
New World Syndrome
妄想徒レジスタンス
Resistance to delusions
クラクラしてないかい？
Are you feeling dizzy?
理論武装過剰オーバーヒート！
Theoretical armament excess, overheat!
白熱のハートビート
Incandescent heartbeat
上等さ snowstorm
It's fine, snowstorm
せわしくなりそうだ！
It's going to be busy!
戦場は猛コンジェスチョン
The battlefield is heavy congestion
出会い別れ 変わりゆく世界で
In a world of meetings and partings
どれだけキミを守りゆけるのだろう
How much will I be able to keep protecting you?
電脳とアンバランス あふれそう大変！
Cyber and unbalance, overflowing mess!
コンニチハ・バーチャライズ 退屈はカスタマイズ！？
Hello virtualize, boredom is customized!?
繰り返す日々 増える減るプレイヤー
Repeating days, increasing and decreasing players
どれだけの「キミ」を守ってこれたのだろう
How many "you" have I been able to protect?
吹き荒れる世界が 変わってしまっても
Even if the raging world changes
キミはまだキミでいてくれるかい？
Will you still be yourself?
続けよう
Let's continue
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD
アドウは効かない！TRUEな世界
Ads won't work! TRUE world
傷だらけのシッポで今日狂も打ち鳴らせ
With a scarred tail, strike out today again
空回りメルヘンなジョーカー
Spinning-wheels, fairy-tale Joker
妄想で暴走超ハンター
Super hunter running wild with delusions
「誰のこと？」なんて言わないね！？
You won't ask "Who's that?", right!?
ようこそ。
Welcome.
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD
ホンネを言っちゃおうか たて前もホコも
Shall I tell you my true feelings? Principles and contradictions too
セイギもギセイも苦手だ
Justice and sacrifice, I'm bad at those
平和がイチバンじゃないかぃ！？
Isn't peace the best!?
でもでもでもファイアークライアー魑魅魍魎なんでもこいやだ！
But but but, fire, cryer, monsters, bring it all on!
キミと生きてく世界なら
If it's a world living with you
アーユーレディ
Are you ready?
僕らの
Our
KINGWORLD
アドウはいらない！TRUEな世界
I don't need ads! TRUE world
キミもヤミも営美も詰め込んで！
Pack in you, the darkness, and the aesthetic!
壮絶なアンリアル クリックザノート
Sublime unreal, click the note
魂に触れたらセイヴザライブ
If you touch the soul, save the live
誰でもきっと叫ぶだろう
Surely anyone would shout
「ようこそ。」
"Welcome."
終わらない僕らの
Our never-ending
KINGWORLD
そう願う僕のTRUEな世界
The TRUE world I wish for
夢もキズも全部全部詰め込んで！
Dreams and scars, pack it all in!
電脳王様はまだまだ夢の中
The cyber king is still in a dream
アイノウ混沌とワンダーランド
I know chaos and wonderland
ユートピアのサキのサキのサキ
Beyond the beyond of the beyond of utopia
ようこそ。
Welcome.
僕らがKINGWORLD
We are the KINGWORLD
INTERNET YAMERO
インターネットエンジェルという現象は
The phenomenon known as the Internet Angel...
仮定された有機交流電燈の
is a lovely rainbow-colored illumination...
かわいい虹色の照明です。ホイ！
of a hypothesized organic alternating current lamp. Ho!
あらゆる透明なアカウントの複合体
A complex of all transparent accounts
このクソゴミカスドブみたいな現実を
In this shitty, trashy, ditch-like reality...
忘れさせてあげる慈愛の天使
I'm the angel of mercy who makes you forget
大人のみんなにはナイショだぞ
It's a secret from all the adults
大丈夫 もう何も怖くないから
It's okay, because there's nothing to be afraid of anymore
こんなSNS抜けだして
Let's get out of this social media...
二人で海を見に行くぞ
and go see the ocean together
インターネット・や・め・ろ！
STOP THE INTERNET!
わかる真似をして
Pretending to understand
わかる真似をして なにも知らないね
Pretending to understand, you don't know anything.
アナタ
You.
なにが悲しいの
What makes you sad?
なにが寂しいの
What makes you lonely?
聞こえてる？
Can you hear me?
人が恋しくて
Longing for people,
人がイヤすぎて
hating people too much...
ループ
Loop.
夜が好きなのに
Even though I love the night,
一人じゃ寒くて
it's too cold alone...
震えてる
I'm trembling.
ほんとうは幸せを知っているのに 不幸なフリやめられないね
Even though I actually know happiness, I can't stop pretending to be unhappy.
アンチに負けず 信者に媚びず
Not losing to antis, not pandering to believers,
どんなにノルマを重ねても
no matter how many quotas I fulfill,
一寸先は地獄行き
one step ahead is hell.
いやもう既に冥府魔道
No, I'm already on the road to perdition.
地獄の沙汰も いいね次第
Even the judgment of hell depends on likes.
二連鎖トラップ 蜘蛛の糸
Double chain trap, spider's thread.
こんなに苦しいはずなのに
Even though it should be this painful,
インターネットがやめられないない！
I can't stop the internet!
駆け巡るエクスタシー
Ecstasy running through.
溶けるマイスリー
Melting Myslee.
画面光りだすの
The screen starts to glow.
不安止まらないよ
The anxiety won't stop.
誰か殺してくれ
Someone please kill me.
いやだ死にたくない
No, I don't want to die.
朝は見たくないの
I don't want to see the morning.
ムリだ 死ぬ
It's impossible, I'll die.
アタマが割れていく
My head is splitting apart.
それでもわたしはこのカオスをオタクと歩む ここにしかない光景を見つけに行くから
Even so, I will walk through this chaos with my fans, because I'm going to find a sight that can only be seen here.
あんなにおそろしい乱れたインターネットから この雪みたいに美しい毒電波がきたんだよ
From such a terrifying, chaotic internet, these beautiful poisonous radio waves like snow have come.
カウンセリングを受けたの 先生から「ネットをやめろ」って言われて
I received counseling. The doctor told me, "Stop using the internet."
もうおまえらと会えないと思った瞬間 胸が苦しくて リアルが壊れてもここが良いって思ったの
The moment I thought I couldn't meet you all anymore, my chest tightened. Even if real life breaks, I thought I'd rather be here.
初めてフォローされた日のこと覚えてる こんなわたしを見て 承認してくれた温もり
I remember the day I was first followed. You saw me and gave me the warmth of approval.
もう細かいことはどうでもいいね
Small details don't matter anymore, right?
せーの インターネット最高！
Ready, set... The internet is the best!
ほとばしるエクスタシー
Gushing ecstasy.
甘い夢を見せてマイスリー
Show me a sweet dream, Myslee.
指先で感じる
Feel it at your fingertips.
泳ぐ電子の海 インターネットボーイ
Swimming in the electronic sea, internet boy.
悲しみ舞い散る
Sadness dances and scatters.
暗い闇の中 インターネットゲーム
In the deep darkness, internet game.
アナタのとなり微笑む
Smiling by your side.
忘れないでいてね インターネットガール
Please don't forget, internet girl.
もっと 沸騰 発狂 爆裂 出来たて
More boiling, madness, explosion, freshly made.
アゲ モレ ヤシ イキョシ
Age, More, Yashi, Ikyoshi.
ピザピザにワロタｗｗ お前らこれは
Lol at pizza, pizza, you guys, this is...
ネタじゃなくてガチ恋なんだからね
It's not a joke, it's real love.
クイーンブルーハワイイエッサー！
Queen Blue Hawaii, yes sir!
無理ポ お前がな これも削除
Muripo, you too, delete this as well.
ググれ 日本語でおk
Google it, OK in Japanese.
１ニノサーンｗｗｗ ハイ！ハイ！
1, 2, 3... lol! High! High!
ズボンボ 坊田 判事まで来た
Zubonbo, Bouda, even the judge came.
アゲ モレ ヤシ イキョシ ハイ！イェッサー！
Age, More, Yashi, Ikyoshi, High! Yes sir!
好き 好き 好き...
Like, like, like...
青白いモニター越しの光を通し オタクの孤独を癒やして回る
Passing through the light of the pale blue monitor, I go around healing the loneliness of the otakus.
わたしはインターネットの天使なのだ
I am the angel of the internet.
はい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
皆さん、こんバッキーつね！
Everyone, Kon-baki-tsune!
あ、あれやっときますか。
Ah, shall we do that thing?
ふわふわしっぽの五目狐
Fluffy-tailed Gomoku Fox...
あなたの心の1番星！
...the #1 star in your heart!
白上フブキでーす！わーい！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki! Yay!
本日はですね、白上フブキ生誕祭2023、サブタイトル「LETTER☆彡」にお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Today, thank you for coming to Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Festival 2023, subtitled "LETTER☆彡"!
わーーい！
Waaaay!
やばい、もう最初から結構使っちゃってるんですけども
Oh no, I've already used up quite a lot of energy from the start,
えー、まずは『KING WORLD』と、そして『INTERNET YAMERO』聴いていただきました。
but first you listened to "KING WORLD" and then "INTERNET YAMERO".
いや、『KING WORLD』ね、もうしょっぱなから噛みそうに…なる曲なんですけども、ダンスもいい感じに踊れたんじゃないでしょうか！
Man, "KING WORLD", it's a song where I almost trip over my words from the very beginning... but I think the dance went pretty well!
そして、『インターネットやめろ！やめろ！やめろ！』
And, "Internet, stop! Stop! Stop!"
え、やめられないんですよね。何事もインターネットは。こちらもね、ちょっとダンス踊らせていただきました。めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！
Well, you just can't stop. Anything regarding the internet. I also did a little dance for this one. It was so much fun!
そして、そんな
And then, for that...
今日のですね、ハッシュタグ！上にございます！
Today's hashtag! It's right up there!
#白上フブキ生誕祭2023
#ShirakamiFubukiBirthdayFestival2023
『#白上フブキ生誕祭2023』で、いっぱいスクショしてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots with "#ShirakamiFubukiBirthdayFestival2023". Please look forward to it!
さて、ではですね、今日は完全ソロライブということで、もうね、歌ったり踊ったり、フリーなダンスしちゃったり、楽しんでいこうと思いますので、皆さんもいっぱい楽しんでいってください！
Now then, since today is a full solo live, I'm going to sing, dance, and even do some free dancing and just enjoy myself, so I hope you all have a lot of fun too!
では早速、次の曲行く前にちょっとね、お水を…
Well then, without further ado, before going to the next song, I'll just have a little... water...
お、えーのみつついこうと思いますが、
Oh, I'm thinking of continuing while drinking, but...
えーちょっとお水飲むか。よいしょ。
Let me take a quick sip of water. Up we go.
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Now, let's move on to the next song!
次の曲は、皆さん、
For the next song, everyone...
もちろんこれとかも覚えてますよね？
You all remember this gesture, right?
Hi Fine FOX!! です！
It's "Hi Fine FOX!!"!
いっぱいサイリウム振ってね！
Wave your lightsticks a lot!
Hi Fine FOX!!
作詞・作曲：ハム
Lyrics/Composition: Hamu
こんこんきーつね！
Kon kon kitsune!
私は白上フブキです！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
お歌とお茶とゲームが大好き、オタクなバーチャル狐です！
I love singing, tea, and gaming—I'm an otaku virtual fox!
いろんなことして毎日楽しく活動してるので、
I do all sorts of things and have fun every day,
フブちゃん、フブキ、白上、皆さんお好きに呼んでください！
Fubu-chan, Fubuki, Shirakami—call me whatever you like!
今日がはじめてのひとも
Even those of you here for the first time,
いつも見てくれてるひとも
And those of you who always watch me,
一人一人のチカラで
Through the strength of each and every one of you,
私はここにいます
I am standing right here.
そう 今も
Yes, even now,
ずっと
Always,
変わらないこの場所で
In this unchanging place,
キミもいつだって推したって Welcome Friends!!
Supporting you, whenever, whoever—Welcome Friends!!
まだまだ道の途中
We're still only halfway there,
慌ただしく過ぎる日々は
The days passing by in such a rush
宝物ですよ
Are true treasures, you know.
泣いたってしょげたって大丈夫じゃい！
It's okay to cry or feel down!
笑顔で一緒に Hi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
ココロを歌に重ねて
Layering my heart into the song,
届けましょう My Happy Days
Let's deliver these Happy Days.
はーじまーぼーう！
Hajiman bou!
今日は何をして遊びましょうか？
What shall we play at today?
お茶でも飲んで一息〜って
Let's take a breather with some tea—
もうこんな時間！？
Is it that time already!?
皆さんのことをもーっと知れたら私も幸せなので、
It would make me so happy to get to know you all better,
釣ったり狩ったりアピールしたり、皆さんせーのでご一緒に！
Fishing, hunting, and showing off—everyone, let's go together!
楽しくて飛び跳ねる日も
On days we jump around with joy,
悲しくて落ち込める日も
And on days we're down and out,
皆さんの傍でちょこんと
I'll be right there by your side,
私がここにいます
Right here for you.
そう 今も
Yes, even now,
ずっと
Always,
変わらない想いだから
Because these feelings won't change,
キミと誰だって推したって Welcome Friends!!
With you, supporting anyone—Welcome Friends!!
ますます成長中
Still growing more and more,
同じ時を過ごす今が
Spending this time together right now
幸せなんですよ
Is such a happy thing, you know.
泣いたってしょげたって大丈夫じゃい！
It's okay to cry or feel down!
笑顔で一緒に Hi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
輝く色を重ねて
Layering brilliant colors,
広げましょう My Brand New World
Let's expand this Brand New World.
お空を飛び越えて
Soaring past the sky,
世界を回ったら
Traveling around the world,
宇宙の果てまでも
Even to the ends of the universe,
ココロ通わせよう
Let our hearts connect.
どこだって届けるよ
I'll reach you anywhere,
いつだって願ってるよ
I'm always wishing for it,
誰だって繋がるよ
Connecting with everyone,
ここから始めよう
Let's start from here.
声をあわせて、一緒にせーの！
Lend me your voices, all together now!
白上の歌、皆さんに届け〜！
Shirakami's song, let it reach you all!
Eins! Zwei! Drei! Fox!!
推して推されて、おにーさんもおねーさんも！
Supporting and being supported, brothers and sisters too!
One! Two! Three! Fox!!
ここまでよくできました！
You all did so well up to here!
最後にひとつ！ 3000回でも足りないぞ！ 100万回愛してる！
One last thing! 3,000 times isn't enough! I love you a million times!
これまでを支えてくれた
To everyone who has supported me until now,
皆さんに寄り添いたいなって
I want to be close to you all.
大切な仲間達とこれからも
With my precious friends, from now on too,
今もずっと 大好きなこの場所で
Always, in this place that I love so much.
キミもいつだって推したって Welcome Friends!!
Supporting you, whenever, whoever—Welcome Friends!!
わくわく更新中
Excitement constantly updating,
まだ見ぬ明日も未来も
For the unseen tomorrow and future,
お友達ですよ
We're friends, you know.
泣いたってしょげたって大好きじゃい！
It's okay to cry or feel down, I still love you!
笑顔で一緒に Hi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
ココロを歌に重ねて
Layering my heart into the song,
届けましょう My Happy Days
Let's deliver these Happy Days.
繋ぎましょう Your Shiny Smile
Let's connect your Shiny Smile.
Hi Fine FOX!!
はい！ということで皆さん！
Yes! So everyone!
ついに白上、新しい3Dになりましたー！わー！
Finally, Shirakami has a new 3D model! Yay!
はぁ、やばい。
Phew, that's intense.
ちょっとお水。ちょっとお水、お水。
Need some water. Some water, water.
あ、ここに見えないお水があるんです、お水が。
Ah, there's invisible water here, water.
はい！ということで、えー皆さん、
Yes! So, everyone,
えー白上新しい3Dでーす！わーい！
here's Shirakami's new 3D! Yay!
はい！2Dが新しくなりまして、ついに3Dも新しくなっちゃいました。わー。
My 2D model was updated, and now finally my 3D model is updated too. Yay.
ちょっといっぱい色々見てほしいです。
I want you to see all the different parts.
この尻尾もボリュームィーになりましたよ。すごい！
This tail has also become more voluminous. Amazing!
ぼよんぼよんです。ねー。
It's so bouncy. Right?
お耳もとってもふよふよになりました。
My ears have also become very fluffy.
ぴょこぴょこぴょこ！
Twitch, twitch, twitch!
ね、あ、じゃあちょっとあの挨拶ももう一回この新しいモデルでやっときますか。
Right, ah, well, shall I do that greeting once more with this new model?
ちょっと恥ずかしいですが。よし。
It's a bit embarrassing. All right.
皆さん、こんこんきつねー！
Everyone, Kon Kon Kitsune!
ふあふあ尻尾の五芒星、あなたの心の1番星。白上フブキです！
The five-point star with a fluffy tail, the number one star in your heart. I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
ハイフレンズ！みたいな。
Hi friends! Something like that.
え、わーわー！皆のコメント、わーわー！
Eh, wow, wow! Everyone's comments, wow, wow!
可愛い、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Cute, thank you. Thank you.
え、さて、えー今回ですね、ちょっと変身シーンを入れてみました。
Anyway, this time, I included a transformation scene.
もう完全にね、新しいモデルになるってことは皆さん知らなかったでしょ？
You all didn't know I was getting a completely new model, did you?
白上も告知しなかったからね！
Because Shirakami didn't announce it!
言わなかったのでね、ものすごいびっくりしてくれたと思います。
Since I didn't say anything, I think you must have been really surprised.
白上からの、えー白上の誕生日だけど皆さんへのプレゼ、サプライズプレゼント！いえーい！大成功！
A birthday present from Shirakami, even though it's my birthday, a surprise present for everyone! Yay! A huge success!
はー、やばい。これからね、もっと今日はいっぱい歌おうと思っているのに、
Phew, that's intense. I'm planning to sing many more songs today, but
わいわい疲れてしまう。
I'm getting so excited and tired.
ちなみに、なんですけども、今回のですね、あのライブの選んだ楽曲なんですが、
By the way, about the songs I chose for this live...
まだサブタイトルが「LETTER」ということで、
the subtitle is "LETTER", so
ま、白上の気持ちを含めたような楽曲を選曲させていただきました。
I selected songs that include Shirakami's feelings.
皆に伝えたい思いとか、もうそういうのをね、歌に乗せて今回は歌っていこうと思います。
I want to convey my feelings to everyone, and I'll be singing with those thoughts in mind.
では、早速白上が疲れ果てる前に、次の曲行きたいと思います。
So, before Shirakami gets completely exhausted, I'd like to move on to the next song.
次は三曲連続！えー、一曲目は「KONKON Beats」！
Next is three songs in a row! First song is "KONKON Beats"!
皆さん、ちゃんと手振り覚えてくれてますか？
Everyone, do you remember the hand movements?
よかったらぜひ一緒に踊ってください。
If you'd like, please dance along.
そして二曲目は、DECO*27さんの「スクランブル交際」という曲です。皆さん知ってますか？
And the second song is "Scramble Kousai" by DECO*27. Do you all know it?
これはちょっとですね、白上の、なんか皆にこう持っといてほしいなっていう、
This one is... I really like the part
こうね、歌詞の中にも一番最後にあるところがものすごく好きです。
at the very end of the lyrics, it's a feeling I want everyone to have.
みんなも白上に、嫉妬、嫉妬してほしいなみたいな、
I want everyone to feel a bit jealous of Shirakami,
とか皆のコロコロ変わる気持ちなんかをちょっと歌ってる曲となっております。
and it's a song that sings about everyone's ever-changing feelings.
そして三曲目は、ちょっとまだ秘密。
And the third song is still a secret for now.
でもね、きっと聞いたことある曲だと思いますので、最後まで楽しんでください。
But I think it's a song you've probably heard before, so please enjoy until the end.
ではでは、まず一曲目。「KONKON Beats」。聞いてください。
Well then, the first song. "KONKON Beats". Please listen.
Everything's gonna be alright って感じよ
Feeling like everything's gonna be alright
今、噂の Bewitch you
Right now, the rumored Bewitch you
KONKON Beats
作詞・作曲：TOKOTOKO
Lyrics & Composition: TOKOTOKO
沈む太陽におはよう って言ったり
Saying "Good morning" to the setting sun
真昼の月におやすみ って言ったり
Saying "Good night" to the midday moon
いつだって僕らはちょっとズレてる
We're always a little bit out of sync
丸い地球のせいかもね
Maybe it's the round Earth's fault
他人事みたいじゃん… だって狐だし
It sounds like someone else's problem... because I'm a fox
そこんとこよろしくね
Take care of that for me
世界中が輪！ ってそれ無理じゃない？ってことも
Thinking "The whole world in a circle! Isn't that impossible?"
今からホントになる
It's going to become real starting now
Are you ready? こんこんこん
Are you ready? Kon kon kon
こんな狐に化かされて
Being bewitched by a fox like this
Knock Knock Knock 心を開けて
Knock Knock Knock Open your heart
Everything's gonna be alright って感じよ
Feeling like everything's gonna be alright
今、噂の Bewitch you
Right now, the rumored Bewitch you
変なことがあった日でも
Even on days when strange things happen
笑えちゃう僕らがいいね
It's good that we can laugh
そうだ、君が Friend なら無敵じゃない？ってことよ
That's right, if you're my friend, aren't we invincible?
今でも本気にしてる
I still believe it
生まれも育ちも 話す言葉も
Where we were born and raised, the language we speak
趣味も歩幅も 人の愛し方も
Our hobbies, our stride, and how we love people
いつだって僕らはちょっとズレてる
We're always a little bit out of sync
それを大事にしてよ
Please treasure it.
I'm ready コンコンコン
I'm ready, kon-kon-kon.
こんな狐に化かされて
Getting bewitched by a fox like this.
Knock Knock Knock
心を開けて
Open up your heart.
Everything's gonna be alright って感じよ
Feels like everything's gonna be alright.
今は噂の Bewitch you
Now I'm the rumored one, Bewitch you.
もう一回！
One more time!
コンコンコン
Kon-kon-kon
こんな狐に化かされて
Getting bewitched by a fox like this.
Knock Knock Knock
心を開けて
Open up your heart.
Don't stop music!
ほら朝まで行くよ 今
Look, we're going until morning now.
地球の裏にチューニング
Tuning into the other side of the world.
Wow コンコンコン
Wow, kon-kon-kon.
魔法をかけて
Cast a spell.
Uh babe
飽きるまで Be with you
Until you get tired, I'll be with you.
スクランブル交際
Scramble Kousai
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
勿体無いじゃない
Isn't it a waste?
バイバイはないわ
There's no "bye-bye".
もっとスクランブル
More scramble.
結構無理じゃない？
Isn't it pretty impossible?
無い愛数えて
Counting the love that isn't there.
ちょっと苦しくなる
It gets a little painful.
全然笑えない Night
A night where I can't laugh at all.
内緒話
Secret talk,
ずっと聞きたくなる
I want to keep hearing it.
絶対有り得ない
Absolutely impossible.
大体有り得る
Mostly possible.
きっと僕らリアル
We're surely real.
もうこんなんてどうしてくれんの
What are you going to do about this?
なら試しに嫌ってみる？
Then, do you want to try hating me?
バカになってどうぞ
Go ahead and become a fool.
まともな中毒性
A proper addictiveness.
今はインスタントラブがしたい したいよ
Right now, I want to do instant love, I want to.
「好きになって順序踏んで」なんて ねえどうせ
"Fall in love and follow the steps," hey, anyway...
愛に囚われたまま
While being trapped in love...
傷付け合ってサヨナラすんじゃん
We'll just hurt each other and say goodbye.
それならいっそ歪んだ方が正解じゃん
Then it's better to just be distorted, right?
今も消えないほど痛い 痛いの
It hurts so much it won't disappear, it hurts.
壊れるほどに求めた正当性
The legitimacy I sought until I broke.
次も誰かのために
Next time, for someone else again...
欲隠して愛を突くんだ
Hiding desires and stabbing at love.
じっとしてって言ったじゃん
I told you to stay still.
勿体無いじゃない
Isn't it a waste?
バイバイはないわ
There's no "bye-bye".
もっとスクランブル
More scramble.
結構無理じゃない？
Isn't it pretty impossible?
無い愛数えて
Counting the love that isn't there.
ちょっと苦しくなる
It gets a little painful.
へえ まあまあいいじゃんか
Heh, it's pretty good, isn't it?
四つ打つ出会いの衝動
The impulse of a four-beat meeting.
もっともっと頂戴
Give me more and more.
ねえ もっともっと頂戴
Hey, give me more and more.
へえ まあまあいいじゃんか
Heh, it's pretty good, isn't it?
裏打つ別れの衝動
The impulse of an off-beat parting.
もっともっと頂戴
Give me more and more.
ねえ もっともっと頂戴
Hey, give me more and more.
妄想なんとかって歌いたく
Wanting to sing about some delusion or other.
曖昧こそ好きってなる
Ambiguity is what makes it "love".
バカになってどうぞ まともな中毒性
Go ahead and become a fool, a proper addictiveness.
今はインスタントラブがしたい したいよ
Right now, I want to do instant love, I want to.
「好きになって順序踏んで」なんて ねえどうせ
"Fall in love and follow the steps," hey, anyway...
愛に囚われたまま
While being trapped in love...
傷付け合ってサヨナラすんじゃん
We'll just hurt each other and say goodbye.
それならいっそ歪んだ方が正解じゃん
Then it's better to just be distorted, right?
今も消えないほど痛い 痛いの
It hurts so much it won't disappear, it hurts.
壊れるほどに求めた正当性
The legitimacy I sought until I broke.
次も誰かのために
Next time, for someone else again...
欲隠して愛を突くんだ
Hiding desires and stabbing at love.
それでもあなたを愛したことだけが
Even so, only the fact that I loved you...
消えてくれやしない しないよ
Won't disappear for me, it won't.
いつになって誰を愛したとて
No matter when or who I love...
僕の心の中で進化するんだ
It evolves inside my heart.
息をするんだ
It takes a breath.
じっとしてって言ったじゃん
I told you to stay still.
Cherry Cherry Bomb!
チェリボム
Cherry Bomb
作詞・作曲：クボナオキ
Lyrics & Composition: Naoki Kubo
弾けて
Pop!
もっと甘く熟して
Ripen even sweeter.
どこまでもあたしを愛して
Love me to the ends of the earth.
弾けて
Pop!
もっと甘く熟してね
Ripen even sweeter, okay?
あ ちゅくちゅく
Ah, chuku-chuku.
Cherry Cherry Bomb!
真っ赤に染まった cherry heart
A cherry heart dyed bright red.
衝撃的なほどに初な
Shockingly innocent.
いわゆる初恋
A so-called first love.
いわゆる初恋みたいな恋
A love like a first love, you could say
どうにかなっちゃいそう cherry heart
Something's about to happen, cherry heart
爆発的威力で君はあたしを虜にしたの
With explosive power, you've captivated me
キュンとしちゃうでしょ
It makes your heart skip a beat, right?
つっつかれすぎて
Being poked too much
もっともっと真っ赤になっちゃうの
Getting redder and redder
弾けてもっと甘く熟して
Burst and ripen even sweeter
どこまでもあたしを愛して
Love me wherever you go
cherry cherry bomb!
弾けてもっと甘く熟してね
Burst and ripen even sweeter, okay?
ah chuku chuku cherry cherry bomb
トロトロトロトロ溶けちゃう
Melting, melting, melting away
あたしの１番弱いとこ
My weakest spot
もうどうにかなっちゃいそう cherry heart
I'm about to lose it, cherry heart
ソワソワソワソワしちゃう
Getting all restless
あなたの１番弱いとこ
Your weakest spot
どうにかしてあげるわ
I'll do something about it
キュンとしちゃうでしょ
It makes your heart skip a beat, right?
つっつかれすぎて
Being poked too much
もっともっと真っ赤になっちゃうの
Getting redder and redder
弾けてもっと熱く熟して
Burst and ripen even hotter
絶対的にあたしを愛して
Love me absolutely
cherry cherry bomb!
弾けてもっと熱く熟してね
Burst and ripen even hotter, okay?
ah chuku chuku cherry cherry bomb
男の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Boys too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
女の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Girls too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
男の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Boys too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
女の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Girls too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
男の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Boys too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
女の子も cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
Girls too, cherry bomb! cherry bomb!
cherry! cherry! cherry! cherry! bomb!
いや、だめ No No No No!
No, wait... No No No No!
弾けてもっと甘く熟して
Burst and ripen even sweeter
どこまでもあたしを愛して
Love me wherever you go
cherry cherry bomb!
弾けてもっと甘く熟してね
Burst and ripen even sweeter, okay?
ah chuku chuku cherry cherry bomb
弾けてもっと熱く熟して
Burst and ripen even hotter
絶対的にあたしを愛して
Love me absolutely
cherry cherry bomb!
弾けてもっと熱く熟してね
Burst and ripen even hotter, okay?
ah chuku chuku chuku chuku chuku chuku
cherry cherry bomb!
はい！ということでチェリーボムでした！ありがとうございましたー！
Alright! So that was 'Cherry Bomb'! Thank you so much!
いやー、ギター重いですね。よいしょっと。
Wow, the guitar is heavy. Up we go.
おいとくか、こちらに。
I'll just put it down over here.
はい、今回はね、こちらのブライト衣装でやってみました！イエーイ！
Yes, this time I tried it with this Bright outfit! Yay!
三宅くんもありがとう。うっ、うっ、ありがとう。
Miyake-kun, thank you too. Uh, uh, thank you.
はい、いやー、もうチェリーボムね、本当に大好きな曲で。
Yes, wow, 'Cherry Bomb' is a song I really love.
前にね、まつりちゃんと、あの最彩の革命を歌ったことがあるんですけど、今回はソロでの、え、チェリーボムでした！
A while ago, I sang 'Saisai no Kakumei' with Matsuri-chan,
but this time it was a solo 'Cherry Bomb'!
この歌詞もですね、もうあの、すごいキュンキュンするような歌詞になってて。
The lyrics too, they're the kind that
really make your heart flutter.
なんかね、白上の気持ちとかも入ってるような、え、本当に素敵な歌となっております。
It feels like it has some of Shirakami's feelings in it,
it's a truly wonderful song.
ぜひ原曲も聴いてみてくださいね。
Please do listen to the original song as well.
あの、好きなとこ、好きなとこと言いますか、すごい歌ってすごいよかったなって思ったとこなんですけど。
The part I like, or rather, the part I felt
really good about singing...
あの、『いや、だめ No No No No』がちょっとね、可愛く歌えてよかったかなって思いまーす。
...was the 'No, wait... No No No No' part,
I think I managed to sing it cutely, which was nice.
さてさてさて、じゃあちょっと、次の曲もありますので、
Now then, now then, now then... there's another song coming up,
ではここで一旦、次の楽曲用の衣装にチェンジしていきましょうか。
so let's change into the outfit for the next one.
よし。
Alright.
はい！ということで、次はお、水着でございます！
Yes! And so, next up is... the swimsuit!
このね、あの、新しい白上での水着のお披露目は今日が初ですね。
This is the first time I'm revealing
this new Shirakami swimsuit today.
ねー、もう寒くなってきて...
Yeah, it's getting colder already...
と思うんですが、
...I think, but,
ちょっと夏らしい曲を歌おうかなと思います。
I think I'll sing a summer-like song.
おっしょ... ちょっとね、ギター持った腕がちょっと痛いんですけども...
Whew... You know, my arms from holding the guitar hurt a bit, but...
このまま頑張って歌いたいと思います！
I'll keep doing my best and sing just like this!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
「青と夏」
"Ao to Natsu"
青と夏
作詞・作曲：大森元貴
Ao to Natsu
Lyrics & Composition: Motoki Ohmori
涼しい風吹く 青空の匂い
A cool breeze blows, the scent of the blue sky
今日はダラッと過ごしてみようか
Shall we spend today lazing around?
風鈴がチリン ひまわりの黄色
Wind chimes tinkle, the yellow of sunflowers
私には関係ないと 思っていたんだ
I thought it had nothing to do with me
夏が始まった 合図がした
The signal sounded that summer has begun
傷つき疲れるけどいいんだ
It hurts and I get tired, but that's okay
次の恋の行方はどこだ
Where is the next love headed?
映画じゃない 主役は誰だ
It's not a movie, who's the protagonist?
映画じゃない 僕らの番だ
It's not a movie, it's our turn
優しい風吹く 夕焼けのまたね
A gentle breeze blows, a "see you later" in the sunset
わかっているけど いつか終わる
I know, but it will end someday
風鈴がチリン スイカの種飛ばし
Wind chimes tinkle, spitting watermelon seeds
私にも関係あるかもね
Maybe it has something to do with me too
友達の嘘も 転がされる愛も
Friends' lies, and love that's pushed around
何から信じていいんでしょうね
I wonder what I should believe in
大人になってもきっと 宝物は褪せないよ
Even when we grow up, our treasures won't fade
大丈夫だから 今はさ
It's okay, for now
青に飛び込んで居よう
Let's dive into the blue
夏が始まった 恋に落ちた
Summer has begun, I fell in love
もう待ち疲れたんだけど どうですか？
I'm already tired of waiting, how about you?
本気になればなるほど辛い
The more serious you get, the more it hurts
平和じゃない 私の恋だ
It's not peaceful, it's my love
私の恋だ
It's my love
寂しいな やっぱ寂しいな
It's lonely, after all it's lonely
いつか忘れられて しまうんだろうか
I wonder if I'll be forgotten someday
それでもね 「繋がり」求める
But even so, I seek "connection"
人の素晴らしさを信じてる
Believing in the wonderfulness of people
運命が突き動かされてゆく
Destiny is being set in motion
赤い糸が音を立てる
The red string of fate is making a sound
主役はあなただ
You are the protagonist
夏が始まった 君はどうだ
Summer has begun, how about you?
素直になれる勇気はあるか
Do you have the courage to be honest?
この恋の行方はどこだ
Where is this love headed?
映画じゃない 愛しい日々だ
It's not a movie, it's precious days
恋が始まった 合図がした
Love has begun, the signal sounded
今日を待ちわびたなんて良い日だ
What a good day, having waited so long for today
まだまだ終われない この夏は
This summer can't end yet
映画じゃない 君の番だ
It's not a movie, it's your turn
映画じゃない 僕らの青だ
It's not a movie, it's our blue
映画じゃない 僕らの夏だ
It's not a movie, it's our summer
はい、ということで、
Yes, so with that,
After Summerでした。
that was 'After Summer'.
ありがとうございましたー。
Thank you very much!
いやー、もう、この曲ね、背景はものすごく、
Yeah, for this song, the background was really,
あのー、スポーツな感じだったんですけど、
uh, very sporty,
白上は、あの、ま、夏といえば水着ということでね、
but since summer means swimsuits for Fubuki,
水着のお披露目も兼ねて、出させていただきました。
I performed while also showing off my swimsuit.
いやー、この曲もなんかこう、
Yeah, this song also kind of,
自分たちの胸に訴えかけてくるような曲で、ねー。
speaks directly to our hearts, doesn't it?
いやもう白上も、この夏、皆さんの心の中では
Fubuki also enjoyed this summer so much,
主役になれたんじゃないかなと思うぐらいね、
that I think I might have become the lead role
あの、いっぱい楽しんだのでね、はい。
in everyone's hearts.
ちょっと恥ずかしいですな。
It's a bit embarrassing.
恥ずかしいですな、改めて水着。はい。
Seeing the swimsuit again is embarrassing. Yes.
ではですね、えー、ちょっと、ふぅー、
Well then, uh, whew,
汗もちょっとヤバいですけども、
the sweat is a bit bad but,
えー、次の曲、行きましょう。
uh, let's go to the next song.
次の曲は、ちょっと皆さんに近い
For the next song, I think I'll sing
真ん中のホールで歌っちゃおうかなと思いますー。
in the center hall, closer to everyone.
次の曲はですね、なんと、皆さん、
The next song, everyone, is one that
白上、ついにこのステージで歌うことができます。
Fubuki can finally sing on this stage.
FUNKY MONKEY BABYSさんの『希望の唄』。
FUNKY MONKEY BABYS's 'Kibou no Uta'.
もう白上が本当に、ファンモの中で一番大好きな曲です。
It's really Fubuki's favorite FunMon song.
歌枠の時も、いつかステージで歌いたいなーって
Do you remember me saying during a stream
言ってたの、すごーく覚えてくれてますかー？
that I wanted to sing it on stage someday?
ね、歌わせていただこうかと思います。
Well, I'm going to sing it now.
お、ヤバイヤバイ。ちょっと、一口、
Oh, wait. Let me take a sip,
お水、お水飲んでからステージ行きますね。
a sip of water before going to the stage.
では、『希望の唄』、聴いてください。
Well then, please listen to 'Kibou no Uta'.
希望の唄
作詞：FUNKY MONKEY BABYS
作曲：FUNKY MONKEY BABYS / 田中隼人
Song of Hope
Lyrics: FUNKY MONKEY BABYS
Composition: FUNKY MONKEY BABYS / Hayato Tanaka
あなたがいて
You are here
あなたといて
I am with you
もしもこの世にあなたが 存在していなかったら
If you didn't exist in this world
100ある笑顔のうち 少なくとも40はなくなる
At least 40 out of 100 smiles would disappear
もしも地球の裏側 あなたがいると分かったら
If I knew you were on the other side of the earth
失った40の笑顔 取り戻すため海を渡る
I'd cross the sea to take back those 40 lost smiles
あなたの涙が雨になる
Your tears become rain
あなたの言葉が風になる
Your words become the wind
諦めかけて乾いた 心に希望という花が咲いた
In my heart that was drying up and about to give up,
a flower called hope bloomed
あぁ 気付いてほしい
Ah, I want you to notice
この唄の意味を知ってほしい
I want you to know the meaning of this song
僕にとってこんなにも 大事で必要な人
Someone so important and necessary to me
あなたがいて
You are here
あなたといて
I am with you
こんなに幸せになるよ
I become this happy
忘れないで そのぬくもり
Don't forget that warmth
他の誰でもないあなた
It's you and no one else
あの涙も
Those tears,
その笑顔も
that smile,
あの涙も
those tears,
その笑顔も
that smile.
この無数にある出会いの中
Among these countless encounters,
偶然あなたと繋がった
I connected with you by chance
もしも出会えてなかったら
If we hadn't met,
夢すら持ててなかった
I wouldn't even have had dreams
いつの間にかあなたの笑顔が
Before I knew it, your smile became
変わらない本当の居場所
my unchanging true place
心から支えられている
I'm supported from the bottom of my heart,
だから僕は笑っていられる
so I can keep smiling
共に遠回りとかもしたけど
We took some detours together,
辿って来た夢の足跡
but these are the footprints of the dreams we followed
昔から変わらず今でも
Still the same as always,
たくさんの勇気をありがとう
thank you for so much courage
振り返らずにまた前へと
Moving forward without looking back,
これからも重ねて行く年
the years we'll keep building up
僕には歌しかないけれど
I only have songs, but
ずっと見守ってほしい
I want you to keep watching over me
あなたがいて
You are here
あなたといて
I am with you
こんなに幸せになるよ
I become this happy
忘れないで そのぬくもり
Don't forget that warmth
他の誰でもないあなた
It's you and no one else
この世界で一人だけの
The miracle of meeting you,
あなたに出会えた奇跡が
the only one in this world,
こんな僕を勇気づける
gives me the strength
力があなたにはあるの
and courage I need.
いつも愛してくれた人よ
To the person who always loved me
僕に今 何か出来るなら
If there's anything I can do now
探していた 未来の灯を
the light of the future I was searching for
あなたと分かち合いたい
I want to share it with you
あなたがいて
You are here
あなたといて
I am with you
こんなに幸せになるよ
I become this happy
忘れないで そのぬくもり
Don't forget that warmth
他の誰でもないあなた
It's you and no one else
...ない あなた
...not anyone else but you
この世界で
In this world
一人だけの
the one and only
あなたに出会えた奇跡が
the miracle of meeting you
こんな僕を勇気づける
gives me courage
力があなたにはあるの
that power is within you
あなたがいる
You are here
あなたといる
I am with you
あなたがいる
You are here
あなたといる
I am with you
ラララ...
La la la...
ありがとう
Thank you
見つけてくれてありがとう
Thank you for finding me
受け止めてくれてありがとう
Thank you for accepting me
愛してくれてありがとう
Thank you for loving me
ありがとう
Thank you
憶えていてくれてありがとう
Thank you for remembering me
受け入れてくれてありがとう
Thank you for taking me in
大切をくれてありがとう
Thank you for giving me what's important
ありがとう
Thank you
ありがとう 作詞・作曲：神沢流太
Thank You | Lyrics & Composition: Ryuta Kanzawa
「あなた」に会えてよかったなんて
Saying it was good to meet "you"
どうでもいいほど当たり前でさ
is so obvious it's trivial
だけどね 言わなきゃね
But you know, I have to say it
死んじゃうから僕らは
because we're all going to die
ありがとね 愛してる
Thank you, I love you
ありがとね ありがとね
Thank you, thank you
この声も
This voice
この顔も
this face
この夢も
this dream
この日々も
these days
この過去も
this past
この道も
this path
哀しさも
even the sadness
独りじゃ 独りじゃ
alone, if alone...
この歌も
This song
この夜も
this night
この愛も
this love
戸惑いも
even the confusion
これからも
from now on too
あなたがいて
with you here
僕がいて
and me here
意味を持つ
it all has meaning
ありがとう
Thank you
分け合ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for sharing with me
約束をくれてありがとう
Thank you for the promise
虚しさをくれてありがとう
Thank you for the emptiness
ありがとう
Thank you
理屈など超えてありがとう
Beyond any logic, thank you
極論をくれてありがとう
Thank you for the extremes
大切をくれてありがとう
Thank you for giving me what's important
この声も
This voice
この顔も
this face
この夢も
this dream
この日々も
these days
この過去も
this past
この道も
this path
喜びも
even the joy
独りじゃ 独りじゃ
alone, if alone...
この歌も
This song
この夜も
this night
この愛も
this love
戸惑いも
even the confusion
これからも
from now on too
あなたがいて
with you here
僕がいて
and me here
生きてゆく
I will live on
何度も何度も「ありがとう」を
Over and over again, "thank you"
忘れて忘れて見失って
forgetting, losing sight of it
失して悔やんでまた気づいて
losing it, regretting, then noticing again
何度もあなたを思い出して
recalling you time and time again
変わっていく生活 重ねる歳
Life changes, years pile up
変わっていく自分と変わる今と
My changing self and the changing present
それでもあの日と同じ距離の
But still, at the same distance as that day
声の 愛の あなたがいること
the voice, the love, and you being there
わかったよ
I realized it
ありがとう
Thank you
...ありがとう
...Thank you.
あなたの願いと　祈りと　迷いと
Along with your wishes, prayers, and hesitations,
孤独と　夢と　明日と　僕も共に生きるよ
Loneliness, dreams, and the future, I will live through them with you.
あなたがその想いをくれたんだよ
Because you gave those feelings to me.
「あなたに会えてよかった」なんて
Saying things like, "I'm glad I met you,"
どうでもいいほど当たり前でさ
is so obvious it's almost trivial.
だけどね　言わなきゃね　死んじゃうから僕らは
But I have to say it, because we're mortal after all.
ありがとね
Thank you.
あいしてる
I love you.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ライブの途中ですがッチャー！
Sorry for the interruption during the live!
グッズ紹介担当のホワイトブリニャンだにゃ！
I'm White Burinyan, in charge of goods promotion, nya!
監獄から収録とか意味わかんないけど、
I don't get why I'm recording from prison, but...
まあシゴデキなところ見せちゃおうかにゃ？
...I guess I'll show you how efficient I am, nya?
緊張しすぎてMCで喋ることほぼ喋れてない
On behalf of the poor Fubunyan who's so nervous
可哀想なフブニャンに代わってお知らせです！
she barely said anything she planned for her MC!
今年もございます！2023年誕生日記念グッズ！
They're here again! The 2023 Birthday Celebration Goods!
ブリニャンのためにいっぱい買ってね！
Buy lots of them for Burinyan's sake, okay!
まずはこちら、
First up is this:
みんなでだらだらアクリルジオラマスタンド！
The "Lazily Together Acrylic Diorama Stand"!
イラストはりぃちゅさんが担当してくれました。
The illustration was done by Riichu-san.
こういうジオラマってキャラクターと背景の間に
With these kinds of dioramas, you can slip postcards
ポストカードとかチェキとか挟んで立て掛けられたり、
or chekis between the characters and the background...
インテリアとしても使えるんじゃないかな？
...so you can use it as interior decor too, right?
あれれ？もしかしてブリニャン天才じゃん？
Oh? Is Burinyan a genius or what?
新衣装のお部屋スタイルでだらだら〜なデザインとなってま〜す！
It's a "lazy" design featuring her loungewear outfit!
続いては、
Moving on:
バックステージパスケース！
The "Backstage Pass Case"!
ライブをお手伝いしてくれるスタッフすこん部君になれちゃうぞい！
You can become a Staff Sukonbu-kun helping out with the live!
イベントなどで名刺として使うもよし、
You can use it for business cards at events,
お仕事などでも使える人は使ってね！
or use it at work if you can!
ブリニャンも担当君にプレゼントしちゃおかな、
Maybe Burinyan will give one to her manager...
名前はもちろんブリニャン！ってつける。
...I'll write "Burinyan!" as the name, obviously.
すこん部君のお耳の再現もすごいね！
The reproduction of Sukonbu-kun's ears is amazing!
裏面はなんか前にフブニャンがみんなと話し合って
For the back, Fubunyan talked with everyone before
こういうのいいねっていうのを取り入れたんだって、
and incorporated things they thought would be cool.
シゴデキじゃん、えらピッピ！
So efficient! Good job!
洋服衣装のスカートにあるデザインが型押しで入ってるよ！
It's embossed with the design from her skirt!
続いて！ランダムラバーキーホルダー！
Next! The "Random Rubber Keychain"!
イラストはやなのんさんが担当！
The illustration is by Yananan-san!
超絶最高なラバーキーホルダー！
These are absolute top-tier rubber keychains!
かわちくてブリニャンこれ大好き！
They're so cute, Burinyan loves them!
通常衣装、部屋着衣装、洋服衣装に
There are keychains for her standard, loungewear,
フブらコスプレのラバーキーホルダー！
and dress outfits, plus a Fubura cosplay one!
オタク君の鞄につけるもよし、
You can put them on your bag, Otaku-kun,
さっきのバックステージパスにつけるのもいいかも！
or even on that backstage pass from earlier!
ちなみに汚れたラバーキーホルダーには
By the way, I heard if a rubber keychain gets dirty,
除光液を綿棒につけて擦るといいらしいって聞いたんだけど、ガチ？
you can clean it with nail polish remover on a Q-tip. Is that legit?
最後は、まさかの、フブキの部屋着ジャージ！
Lastly, believe it or not: Fubuki's Loungewear Jersey!
ひぇ〜ブリニャンも欲し〜！
Whoa~ Burinyan wants one too!
男女兼用サイズだから、担当君にも着せられちゃうね！
It's unisex, so I can make my manager wear it too!
普段使いしやすいシンプルなデザインだし、
It's a simple design that's easy to wear daily,
これまで出したTシャツにも合うんじゃないかにゃ？
and I bet it'll go well with previous T-shirts too, nya!
オタク君たちのジャージ姿、ブリニャンも見てみたいにゃ！
Burinyan wants to see you Otaku-kuns in your jerseys, nya!
ねえ、お揃っちにしようにゃ！
Hey, let's get matching ones, nya!
は？
What?
今嫌だって言った？
Did you just say "no thanks"?
そして今回もございます！
And we have it this time as well!
数量限定フルセット購入特典、直筆サインにゃ！
The limited edition full set purchase bonus: an autograph, nya!
今回は初のチェキ風ブロマイド！
This time, it's our first cheki-style bromide!
見てこれ、寝顔ふにゃふにゃで超うけ！
Look at this, her sleeping face is so soft, it's hilarious!
アイドルの寝起きが激写ってこと？
A candid shot of an idol waking up?
究極のお宝じゃん！
This is the ultimate treasure!
まあブリニャンはこういう寝顔とか絶対見せないけどね！
Though Burinyan would never show a sleeping face like that!
以上、今年の誕生日グッズの紹介でした！
That's all for this year's birthday goods!
引き続きライブを楽しんでいってくださいにゃ！
Please continue to enjoy the live, nya!
もうすぐ時計は６時
The clock is almost at six.
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already there.
影を踏んで
Stepping on shadows,
夜に紛れたくなる
wanting to disappear into the night,
帰り道
on the way home.
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I look for it...
一つしかない星
The one and only star
何億光年　離れたところから
From hundreds of millions of light years away
あんなに輝く
Shining so brightly
いいな　君は
You're so lucky
みんなから愛されて
Being loved by everyone
いいや　僕は
Actually, I
ずっと一人きりさ
Have always been all alone
君と集まって　星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜　一瞬の願い事
A fleeting wish on a starry night
きらめいて　ゆらめいて
Sparkling, swaying
震えてるシグナル
A trembling signal
君と集まって　星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて　指を指されるような
Like being pointed at while looking up at the sky
つないだ線　解かないで
Don't undo the lines we've connected
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzlingly I shine
もうすぐ時計は８時
The clock will soon strike eight
夜空に満天の星
The night sky is full of stars
何億光年　離れたところにはもう
In a place hundreds of millions of light years away
ないかもしれない
They might not even exist anymore
月が綺麗で　泣きそうになるのは
The reason the beautiful moon makes me feel like crying
いつの日か　別れが来るから
Is because one day we'll have to say goodbye
君と集まって　星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたい　流れるひとりごと
My flowing soliloquy is like a comet
消えていく　残像は
The fading afterimage
真夜中のプリズム
Is a midnight prism
君と集まって　星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
切なる願い　誰かに届いたら
If my earnest wish reached someone
変われるかな　夜の淵を
I wonder if I could change, as if tracing
なぞるような　こんな僕でも
The edge of the night, even for someone like me
遥か彼方　僕らは出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we ended up meeting each other
カルマだから　何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because it's karma, we'll keep meeting again and again
雲の隙間で
In the gaps between the clouds
君と集まって　星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜広げて　描こう絵空事
Let's spread out the night and draw a pipe dream
暗闇を　照らすような
Even if it's not a full moon
満月じゃなくたって
That illuminates the darkness
だから集まって　星座になりたい
So I want to gather together and become a constellation
色とりどりの光　放つような
Emitting lights of all sorts of colors
つないだ線　解かないよ
I won't undo the lines we've connected
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling you are
泡沫
Utakata (Bubble)
平凡すぎて　くだらない世界
A world that's too ordinary and worthless
閉ざしてた　誰も信じずに
I kept myself closed off, trusting no one
こじ開けたんだ　君が突然に
Then you suddenly pried it open
あの眼差しが僕を救った
That gaze of yours saved me
初めて触れる感情
Emotions I'm feeling for the first time
消えないように　握りしめて
I hold them tight so they won't fade away
繋ぐ心の声
The voice of a heart that connects
まだ見ぬ世界へと
To a world yet unseen
瞳に映っている
What's reflected in my eyes
眩しすぎる今が
Is this moment that's too dazzling
嘘でも　構わない
Even if it's a lie, I don't care
響き続けた声を辿って
Following the voices that kept echoing
いつしかここが　居場所になって
Before I knew it, this place became where I belong
居場所になって
Becoming a place to belong
書き換わっていく毎日の色が
The colors of every day are being rewritten
この先も君と描きたい
I want to draw with you in the future too
淡い光の中
In the faint light
君と駆けてくこの瞬間も
This moment running with you too
変わってしまうのかな
I wonder if it will change
揺れる心の声
The swaying voice of my heart
溢れ出す想いも
And the overflowing feelings
時が過ぎるだけで忘れてゆくなんて
Forgetting just as time passes...
どうしても悔しくて
Is just so frustrating
深い僕の心まで
To the depths of my heart
名前を呼ぶ声が
The voice calling my name
いつまでも続くなんてありえないと
Knowing that "continuing forever"
わかっていたけど
Was impossible, but still...
遠ざかる景色の中
In the receding scenery
また夢を見ていた
I was dreaming again
はい！ということで、Blue Journeyより
Yes! So, from Blue Journey...
「泡沫」をお聞きいただきました。ありがとうございます！
you just heard "Utakata". Thank you very much!
そして、Blue Journey 以上でございます！
And that's all for Blue Journey!
いやもう本当にこの衣装、めちゃめちゃ可愛いので
Really, this outfit is so incredibly cute...
こうやってね、新しいお姿でのお披露目もできて嬉しいです！
so I'm happy to be able to show it off in my new form!
さてさて、Blue Journeyの楽曲もね、ライブを見に来てくれた方だとね
Now, regarding the Blue Journey song, those who came to see the live performance...
ふと2人足りないんじゃないかなと思うんですけども
might have noticed two people missing.
実はこの曲、アキロゼとね、あの、るいねえと3人で歌っておりますので
Actually, this song is sung by Aki Rosenthal and Rui-nee, the three of us.
あの、まだね、あの、「泡沫」楽曲聞いてないよっていう方はぜひとも聞いていただけると嬉しいです！
So, if you haven't heard "Utakata" yet, I'd be happy if you'd give it a listen!
さてさて、まあね、こちらの楽曲、ま、結構ね、切ない感じの楽曲なんですけども
Now, well, this song, it's quite a bittersweet song.
まあ、なんかそういう気持ちの時もみんなあるよね、みたいな曲で
It's like, "everyone has those kinds of feelings sometimes."
ちょっとしんみりしつつも、また夢を見ていたというね
While being a bit sentimental, it's about "dreaming again".
夢落ちという、何とも言えない悲しいような切ないような曲となっておりましたが
A sort of "it was all a dream" ending, an indescribably sad and bittersweet song.
みんなの心にちょっとでも響いてくれたらいいなと思い選曲しました！
I chose this song hoping it would resonate with your hearts even just a little!
さて、ついにつぎで最後の曲です！
Now, finally, the next one is the last song!
最後の曲は、なんと白上フブキオリジナル楽曲となっております！
The last song is actually a Shirakami Fubuki original song!
新曲です！
It's a new song!
もうこちらの楽曲、歌ったあとはもうすぐバイバイになってしまうので
Once I sing this song, it'll be goodbye soon.
ちょっとこの楽曲は、えー、まね、結構白上オリ曲では
So this song, well, compared to my other original songs...
白上からみんなに伝えたいみたいな感じだったんですけども
I usually feel like I'm conveying something to everyone...
今回の新曲は結構ファン目線の楽曲となっておりますので
but this new song is very much from a fan's perspective.
なんかみんなもこういう気持ちでだったらいいなとか
I hope everyone feels like this...
白上はなんかこういう気持ちで推しのこと見てるよっていう歌詞となっておりますので
The lyrics are about how I, Shirakami, look at my favorites with these feelings.
なんか共感していっぱい歌ってくれたらいいなと思っております！
So I hope you can empathize with it and sing along a lot!
では、行きますかね！じゃあ最後の楽曲、白上フブキオリジナル楽曲
Well, shall we go? Then, the final song, a Shirakami Fubuki original song.
聞いてください。「LETTER☆彡」
Please listen. "LETTER☆彡".
Dear My Fave、「ありがとう」を込めて
Dear My Fave, with my "thank you"
君の名は、かけがえのない希望
Your name is my irreplaceable hope
リアルだって頑張れる！
I can do my best in real life too!
たって言葉ひとつで胸が踊る
Just one word makes my heart dance
"限界"と呼ばれたっていい 生きる理由なんです
"Limit"? Call it what you like, it's my reason for living
へこんだって見失ったって また私を照らしてくれる
Even when I'm down or lose my way, you shine on me again
心臓わしづかみされて 氣絶しちゃいそうです
My heart is being gripped so hard, I feel like I'm going to faint
一生懸命な姿に
At your hardworking self
何度も勇気もらったから
Since I've received courage so many times
今度は私がエールになりたい
This time, I want to be your cheer
This time, I want to be the one who cheers you on
唄え 全熱量の賛歌
Sing, an anthem of all my energy
Dear My Fave,
「大好き！」が溢れた
My "I love you!" overflowed
この想い、手紙に書いて贈ります
I'll write these feelings in a letter and send them to you
You made my day,
夢を叶えて
Granting my dreams
君の笑顔が、私の原動力
Your smile is my driving force
You will always be the first star in my heart
どこまでもついてゆくよ！
I'll follow you anywhere!
I'm your biggest fan
「幸せ」って
"Happiness" is...
君と出会って過ごす日々だと定義された！
defined as the days I spend meeting you!
会えない時間だって…良い！
Even the time we can't meet is... fine!
愛を育ててるんです
Because we're nurturing our love
どうしたって 叫びたくなった
No matter what, I wanted to shout
イタズラ顔も 最の高！
Even your mischievous face is the best!
来世も、再来世までも 語り継ぎたいのです
I want to pass this down even to the next life, and the one after that
一瞬一瞬が
Every single moment
ときめくよ
Is thrilling
両手にいっぱいの思い出
Memories overflowing in my hands
確かめ合えば寂しくないから
If we confirm them with each other, we won't be lonely
繋げ 全絆の結晶
Connect the crystal of all our bonds
Dear My Fave,
「がんばって！」なんて言えない
I can't say things like "Do your best!"
「大丈夫」の三文字で
With the three characters for "It's okay"
伝わるかな…
I wonder if it'll get through...
Day by day
そう、君のおかげで
Yes, thanks to you
少しだけ 自分を好きになれたから
I've come to like myself a little more
君らしく being and enjoy yourself
Be true to yourself, being and enjoy yourself
心から願う私がいる
I'm here, wishing from my heart
ひとりじゃない
You're not alone
Dear My Fave,
「大好き！」を集めた
I gathered all my "I love you!"s
合言葉、手紙に書いて贈ります
I'll write our password in a letter and send it to you
You made my life 夢で終わらない
You made my life, it won't end as a dream
君だけが 君こそが 起こす奇跡
Only you, it's you who creates the miracle
You will always be the first star in my heart☆
信じて 夜空のように ずっと
Believe, like the night sky, forever
I will follow you forever
ありったけの愛を込めて
With all the love I can give
「ありがとう」
"Thank you"
君という たった一つの奇跡
The one and only miracle that is you
銀河を超えて 駆け合うフレーズ 輝かせて
Shining the phrases we call out to each other across the galaxy
Best wishes,
La-la-la-
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
coming soon!!
「大好きな君へ」
"To my beloved you"
今日は私のライブに来てくれて 本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming to my live today.
今年も君と最高の誕生日を迎えられて 嬉しいよ！！
I'm so happy to be able to celebrate my birthday with you again this year!!
この活動は君と私の思い出です。
This journey is the collection of memories of you and me.
いつまでも、これからも沢山の思い出を 作ってゆこうね。
Let's keep making many memories forever from now on.
全力で出走して応援してくれる君に 負けないくらい私も君を”推して”いくよ！！
I will "fave" you just as much as you support me with all your heart!!
君の推しにしてくれてありがとう！！
Thank you for making me your fave!!
100万回愛してる！！
I love you a million times over!!
君の推しより
From your fave